Guide to the Cleanth Brooks Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Additions Since 1978, 1926-1994; Series VII; 29.92; (34 boxes)
  - January 1995 Acquisition, 5.25' (6 boxes)
    - As I Lay Dying, 1976, undated (Box 123)
    - "Walsh's Garland Bibliography", 1980-1984 (Box 123)
    - "Reviews of Faulkner's Books", 1948-1962, undated (Box 123)
    - "Correspondence re Faulkner (My Earlier)", 1959-1963 (Box 123)
    - The Yoknapatawpha Country, 1953-1966 (Box 123)
    - "My 'Elmer' notes", undated (Box 123)
    - "Reviews of Books by Faulkner", 1950-1961, undated (Box 123)
    - Toward Yoknapatawpha, early, heavily corrected drafts, 1968, undated (Box 123)
    - "Thesis on My Poetic Theory Directed by Vivas", 1950 (Box 123)
    - "Personal Bibliography 1978- ", 1980-1984, undated (Box 123)
    - "Walsh's Summaries of Lit Crit: A Short History and Mod. Poetry and the Tradition", undated (Box 123)
    - "History, Faulkner's Ideas on Millgate", 1976, undated (Box 123)
    - "K. A. Porter", 1967, undated (Box 123)
    - "F on Sherwood Anderson", undated (Box 123)
    - Walsh, John, 1964-1988, undated (Box 123)
    - "Requests to Reprint", 1952-1985, undated (Box 123)
    - "Indra", 1981, undated (Box 123)
    - "McGehee U of T", 1956-1980, undated (Box 123)
    - "The Times Between" (Prunty), undated (Box 123)
    - Langford, Gerald, 1979 (Box 123)
    - "Derrida on the Mend: A Reinstatement of Poetic Presence" (Magliola), 1981, undated; 2 folders (Box 123)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 123)
    - "The Simplicaid; a Satirco-Didactic Poem", undated (Box 123)
    - "Jefferson Lec. Clippings", 1983-1986 (Box 123)
    - "C. T. Indra Correspondence", 1982-1986 (Box 124)
    - "Indra MS re Brooks", 1982, undated (Box 124)
    - Winchell, Mark, 1993, undated (Box 124)
    - "Lecture Texts Box K", undated (Box 124)
    - "17th Century Poems & Indra Text Box L", 1957-1985, undated (Box 124)
    - "Text of Lecture as Given in Ito, Japan, April 1985 - Faulkner Conference", undated (Box 124)
    - "T. S. Eliot and 'Modernism'", undated (Box 124)
    - "Literature in a Technological Age", undated (Box 124)
    - "T. S. Eliot and the American South", undated (Box 124)
    - "How Not to Read a Poem", undated (Box 124)
    - Newspaper clippings and notes, 1972, undated (Box 124)
    - "Jefferson Various Notes and Sub-Sections", 1965-1985, undated (Box 124)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1985, undated (Box 124)
    - "Jefferson Lecture Materials", 1984-1985 (Box 124)
    - "Atrocious Prose - Two Samples", undated (Box 124)
    - "Decay of the Language", 1961-1984, undated (Box 124)
    - "Notes on F. Articles", undated (Box 124)
    - Calendars and diaries, 1948-1973; 26 folders (Box 125)
    - Cards relating to Percy letters and twentieth century poets, undated (Box 126)
    - "Review of Faulkner's Books", 1948-1962, undated (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - The Yoknapatawpha Country, 1953-1966 (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - "Reviews of Books by Faulkner", 1950-1961, undated (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - Newspaper clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - "Jefferson Lec. Clippings", 1983-1986 (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - "Jefferson Various Notes and Sub-Sections", 1965-1985, undated (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - "Jefferson Lecture Materials", 1984-1985 (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - "Decay of the Language", 1961-1984, undated (Box 127 (Oversize))
  - September 1995 Acquisition, 0.42' (1 box)
    Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 459.
    - Community, Religion, and Literature, draft, undated; 3 folders (Box 128)
    - "In Search of the New Criticism", undated (Box 128)
    - Community, Religion, and Literature, proof, 1994; 5 folders (Box 128)
  - September 1995 Acquisition, 1.00' (1 box)
    Gift of John Walsh.
    Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 445.
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1960-1988, undated (Box 129)
    - Correspondence relating to Tinkum's death, 1985-1989 (Box 129)
    - "Book Contracts & Legal Papers", 1989 (Box 129)
    - Winchell, Mark, 1990-1992, undated (Box 129)
    - "Essays for LSU Book", 1986, undated (Box 129)
    - "Faulkner and Christianity", undated (Box 129)
    - Calendars and diaries, 1964-1979; 12 folders (Box 129)
- Oversize, 1932-86; 2; (1 box)
  Oversize contains material from Series II, IV, and VI and is arranged in the same order as material in those series.
  - WRITINGS
    - Percy Editorial Project
      - Correspondence
        - Percy-Pinkerton: copies, n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1986)
        - Percy-Warburton: copies, n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1987)
      - Subject files
        - Percy family genealogical records, n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1988-89)
    - Books
      - Understanding Poetry
        - Mechanicals, n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1990)
      - William Faulkner: The Yoknapatawpha Country
        - Publicity, 1963 Nov 24 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1991)
    - Shorter Works
      - Essays and lectures
        Printed material
        - Posters, 1982-86 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1992)
  - PROFESSIONAL PAPERS
    - Subject Files
      - Agrarian Movement, 1980 Oct 31 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1993)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Biographical Material
      - Miscellaneous material, 1932, n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1994-95)
      - Photographs
        Brooks, Cleanth: group shots
        - Fugitives and critics [extended group], 1956 May 4 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 1996)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 1966-81, n.d.; 0.5; (1 box)
  Box 95 contains 11 sound recordings on magnetic tape in various sizes.
  Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Pertaining to American Literature: The Makers and the Making. Interview between Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, tape 2, 1972 June 26; 1 (Box 95, Folder 1997, Item barcode 39002104618088)
    Note on envelope: "This has been transcribed and transferred to another tape. But do not erase yet."
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Pertaining to American Literature: The Makers and the Making. Interview between Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, tape 3, undated; 1 (Box 95, Folder 1998, Item barcode 39002104618096)
  - Pertaining to American Literature: The Makers and the Making. Interview between Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, tape 4, 1972 July 26; 1 (Box 95, Folder 1999, Item barcode 39002104618104)
  - Pertaining to American Literature: The Makers and the Making. Interview between Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, tape 5, undated; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2000, Item barcode 39002104618112)
  - Pertaining to American Literature: The Makers and the Making. Interview between Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, tape 6, undated; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2001, Item barcode 39002104618120)
  - Pertaining to American Literature: The Makers and the Making. Interview between Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, Tapes 1-4, undated; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2002, Item barcode 39002104618138)
  - Pertaining to An Approach to Literature. Interview between Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, undated; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2003, Item barcode 39002104618146)
  - Pertaining to "Cultural Attaché Material". "The Voices of America: A Sound Documentary of the Festival of American Arts and Humanities," London, narrated and produced by John Whiting [American Embassy, London, England], 1966; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2004, Item barcode 39002104618161)
  - Pertaining to "Interviews". Interview with Cleanth Brooks by Wroy Herbert for the American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, Washington, D.C., I, 1971 October; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2005, Item barcode 39002104618179)
  - Pertaining to "Interviews". Interview with Cleanth Brooks by Wroy Herbert for the American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, Washington, D.C., II, 1971 October; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2006, Item barcode 39002104618187)
  - Pertaining to "Interviews". Interview with Cleanth Brooks by Wroy Herbert for the American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, Washington, D.C., III, 1981 October; 1 (Box 95, Folder 2007, Item barcode 39002104618153)